这是一个男孩遇见女孩的故事
This is a story of boy meets girl.
男主角汤姆·汉森  来自新泽西州的马盖特
The boy, Tom Hansen of Margate, New Jersey,
打小就认定他不会真正的幸福...
grew up believing that he'd never truly be happy...
直到遇见他的心上人
until the day he met "the one."
这个想法来自于早期接触的悲伤英国流行音乐
This belief stemmed from early exposure to sad British pop music...
和对整部 毕业生 的误读
and a total misreading of the movie The Graduate.
依莲  依莲
Elaine! Elaine!
女主角莎莫·芬恩  来自密歇根州的辛尼克
The girl, Summer Finn of Shinnecock, Michigan
却不这么想
did not share this belief.
自从她父母的婚姻破裂之后
Since the disintegration of her parents marriage
她只爱两样东西
she'd only loved two things.
第一是她乌黑的长发
The first was her long dark hair.
而第二是  她可以轻易的把它剪掉
The second was how easily she could cut it off...
却毫不在意
and feel nothing.
Tom 在一月八号那天遇见了 Summer
Tom meets Summer on January 8.
他在那一刻突然明白了 Summer 就是他要找的那个人
He knows almost immediately she's who he's been searching for.
这是个男孩遇见女孩的故事
This is a story of boy meets girl.
但我要先告诉你
But you should know up front
这不是个爱情故事
this is not a love story.
♪ They made a statue of us ♪
♪ And put it on a mountaintop ♪
♪ Now tourists come and stare at us ♪
♪ Blow bubbles with their gum ♪
♪ Take photographs of fun ♪
♪ Have fun ♪
♪ They'll name a city after us ♪
♪ And later say it's all our fault ♪
♪ Then they'll give us a talking to ♪
♪ 'Cause they've got years of experience ♪
♪ Living in a den of thieves ♪
♪ Rummaging for answers in the pages ♪
♪ And it's contagious ♪
我们不知道还能打给谁
We didn't know who else to call.
阿曼达·海勒事件重演
It's Amanda Heller all over again.
你做的很对
You did the right thing.
他现在在哪
Now where is he?
Thomas.
瑞切尔 你怎么在这儿
Rachel. What are you doing here?
我来帮你  怎么帮我
I'm here to help you. Help me how?
首先 把碟子放下
First' put down the plate.
喝了它
Drink this.
- 那是什么  - 伏特加
- What is that? - Vodka.
嗯.. 妈知道你来这儿了吗
Um' does Mom know that you're here?
现在应该快10点了   别担心
'Cause it's probably past 10:00. Don't worry about it.
先从开始讲  告诉我们出什么事了
Just start from the beginning, and tell us what happened.
一切都很好
Things were going so well.
然后呢
Then what?
我认为我们不应该再见面了
I think we should stop seeing each other.
- 就这样   - 就这样
Just like that? Just like that.
- 她说为什么了吗  - 我说这个.. 我们在干什么
- Did she say why? - I mean' this thing - what are we doing?
我的意思是  这很正常吗
I mean, is this normal?
平常.. 不  我不知道  也不在乎  我很开心 你不也是吗
Norm- l- I don't know. I don't care. I'm happy. Aren't you happy?
- 你很开心   - 你不是吗
You're happy? You're not?
- 我们总是在争吵   - 胡说
All we do is argue. That is bullshit.
可能她只是心情不好
Maybe she was just in a bad mood.
对，可能只是.. 激素什么的
Yeah, maybe like a- a hormonal thing.
- P.M.S. （经前综合征） - 你是怎么知道 P.M.S. 的
- P.M.S.? - What do you know about P.M.S.?
- 比你知道的多 Tom  - ..之后呢
- More than you' Tom. - Then what happened?
你不会觉得太意外吧
This can't come as a total surprise to you.
我们像 Sid 和 Nancy 那样 几个月了
I mean, we've been like Sid and Nancy for months now.
Summer     Sid 刺伤了 Nancy ... 七次  用菜刀
Summer, Sid stabbed Nancy... seven times with a kitchen knife.
我的意思是  我们有点分歧  但我认为我才是 Sid Vicious
L- I mean, we have some disagreements, but I hardly think I'm Sid Vicious.
不  我是
No. I'm Sid.
哦  那我是 Nancy 了
Oh, so I'm Nancy?
先吃吧  过会再聊
Let's just eat, and we'll talk about it later.
嗯  味道不错
Mmm. That is good.
真高兴我们点了这些
I'm really glad we did this.
我喜欢这儿的薄饼
I love these pancakes.
怎么了
What?
Tom  别走  你还是我的最好的朋友
Tom, don't go. You're still my best friend!
- 上帝  - 你以前甩过别的女孩
- Jesus. - You've broken up with girls before.
对
Yes.
也有女孩甩过你
And girls have broken up with you before.
这不一样   为什么
This is different. Why?
因为是 Summer
'Cause it's Summer.
所以你要.. 你要再找一个
So you'll-you'll meet somebody new.
重点是 你很棒 你会忘了她
Point is, you're the best guy I know. You'll get over her.
就像俗话说.. 呃..
I think it's kind of like how they say. There's, uh-
海里有很多鱼
There's plenty of other fish in the sea.
- 不对   - 俗话是这么说的 ..
No. They- They say that.
好吧  他们在说谎
Well, they're lying.
我不想忘了她
I don't want to get over her.
我想让她回来
I want to get her back.
可能求稳错了（肯定错了）
Maybe playing it safe is the wrong approach.
家庭的核心要垮了
The nuclear family is dead'
我们需要一个新的假日来认识这点
and we need a new holiday that recognizes that.
5月21号
May 21 st.
另一个母亲节
Other Mother's Day.
谢谢
Thank you.
我觉得很有市场 汉森 你怎么看
I'd say we've got some potential here. What do you think, Hansen?
你能详细的说一下吗
Could you write up some prototypes for these?
Vance 先生  三线有电话找你
Uh' Mr. Vance, there's a telephone call for you on line three.
哦  谢谢  呃.. 各位  这是 Summer 我的新助理
Oh. Thank you. Uh' everyone, this is Summer, my new assistant.
Summer 刚从.. 那什么地方搬来
Summer just moved here from-
密歇根  对 密歇根
Michigan. Right. Michigan. Right.
Summer 这是 "各位"
Uh, Summer, everyone.
各位 这是 Summer    抱歉，我得去接个电话
Everyone, Summer. Excuse me. I have to take this.
见到各位很荣幸
It's nice to meet you all.
世界上只有两种人
There's only two kinds of people in the world.
女人和男人
There's women, and there's men.
Summer 是个女人
Summer Finn was a woman.
身高  平均数  体重  平均数
Height, average. Weight, average.
鞋码 比平均数略小
Shoe size, slightly above average.
从所有的这些看
For all intents and purposes,
Summer 只是普通的女孩
Summer Finn, just another girl.
可事实并不是这样
Except she wasn't.
比如  在1998年
To wit, in 1998,
Summer 在她的高中毕业纪念册上
Summer quoted a song by the Scottish band Belle and Sebastian...
引用了苏格兰贝儿与塞巴斯乐团的一首歌
in her high school yearbook.
" 生命因坎坷而精彩 "
"Color my life with the chaos of trouble."
让他们的唱片 " 系着阿拉伯皮带的男孩 "
This spike in Michigan sales of their album...
在密歇根大卖
The Boy with the Arab Strap...
一直困扰着产业分析家
continues to puzzle industry analysts.
Summer 大二的时候在冰淇淋店打工
Summer's employment at the Daily Freeze during her sophomore year...
这家店的收益也莫名其妙的增加了 212%
coincided with an inexplicable 212% increase in revenue.
每次 Summer 租房
Every apartment Summer rented...
价格都比市场均价低 9.2%
was offered at an average rate of 9.2% below market value.
她上下班的路上
And her round-trip commute to work...
平均每天让人回头 18.4 次
averaged 18.4 double takes per day.
这是很稀有的现象 " Summer 效应 "
It was a rare quality, this "Summer effect."
稀有   却是所有青春期的雄性动物遇到过的
Rare, and yet something every post adolescent male has encountered...
一生中至少一次
at least once in their lives.
对于 Tom  在这城市里 400,000 个办公室
For Tom Hansen to find it now in a city of 400,000 offices,
91,000 栋商业大厦 3,800,000 人里 遇到她
91,000 commercial buildings and 3.8 million people-
唯一的解释就是
well, that could only be explained by one thing:
命运
Fate.
嗨  我听说她是个婊子
Dude, I hear she's a bitch.
是吗
Really?
对  Patel 在复印室跟她搭讪   她甩都不甩
Yeah. Patel tried to talk to her in the copy room. She's totally not having it.
可能她只是很忙
Maybe she was just in a hurry.
也可能她是个高傲女   " 比所有人都优秀 " 真扯蛋
And maybe she's an uppity, "better than everyone" superskank.
小子  我看到了  她很火辣
Damn. I know. She's pretty hot.
真混蛋  为什么漂亮的女孩
That sucks. Why is it pretty girls...
认为她们能把人们当成垃圾  而且还做到了
think they can treat people like crap and get away with it?
上世纪留下的恶习
Centuries of reinforcement.
随便她 跟我没关系
You know what? Screw her. I don't care.
她想那样  随便她
If she wants to be that way, fine.
♪ Driving in your car♪
♪ Oh, please don't drop me home ♪
史密斯
Smiths?
嗨
Hi.
- 我喜欢史密斯  - 什么
I love the Smiths. Sorry?
我说   我喜欢史密斯的歌
I said I love the Smiths.
你   嗯.. 你品位不错
You have- You have good taste in music.
- 你喜欢史密斯的歌   - 对
You like the Smiths? Yeah.
♪ To die by your side is such a heavenly way to die ♪
很棒
I love 'em.
操蛋
Holy shit.
这是你的 再来一块
There you go. Have another piece.
要酒吗
Ah. Drinks?
- 亚瑟   你有蛋糕吗 - 谢谢
Arthur, did you get a piece? Thanks.
- 来一杯  - 好
Want one? Yeah.
- 来一杯  - 嗯
Want one? Mmm.
- Summer  - 恩
Summer, right? Oh. Yeah.
- 史密斯迷  - 哦  我是 Tom
Smiths fan. Yeah. Tom.
- 想要一点吗  - 嗯
Want some, uh, uh-
- 不是香槟 我不知道是什么  - 好吧
It's not champagne. I don't know what it is. Sure.
最近怎么样
So, how's it goin'?
- 很好  - 你刚搬来吧
Pretty good. You just moved here, right?
嗯..  什么时候
Mm-hmm. When?
- 周六  - 哦  哇
Saturday. Oh, wow.
呃 .. 什么把你招来了
And, uh, what brought you?
各种烦人的事
Boredom mostly.
- 想找点新鲜事干  - 嗯
Wanted to try something new and exciting. Mmm.
很明显这里是个好选择
Well, clearly you've come to the right place.
- 那  你会在这呆多久  - 三四年吧
So, have you worked here long? About three or four years.
哇  你..
Wow. You've...
一直很喜欢写贺卡吗
always wanted to write greeting cards?
不  我现在就不想
No, I don't even want to do it now.
那你应该做点别的
Well, you should do something else then.
其实  我是学建筑的
Yeah. I studied to be an architect, actually.
是吗  真棒  然后呢
You did? That's cool. What happened there?
不怎么样
It didn't work out.
我需要一个工作  然后是这样了
I needed a job, and here we are.
有好作品吗
You any good?
好吧  我写了这个
Well, um, I wrote this one.
" 今天你是个男人了
"Today you're a man.
成人礼贺词 "
Mazel tov on your bar mitzvah."
- 很畅销  - 我是说建筑方面
It's a big seller. I meant as an architect.
嗯..
Yeah.
我觉得不行  恩
I doubt it. Well,
你是个写贺卡的高手
you're a perfectly adequate greeting card writer.
多谢  他们在大学经常叫我的外号
Thank you. That was actually my nickname in college.
他们叫我 " 完美Hansen "
They called me "Perfectly Adequate" Hansen.
他们以前叫我 " 肛门女 "
They used to call me Anal Girl.
我以前有洁癖
I was very neat and organized.
我该过去了  所以 .. 呃 ..
Well, I should get back, so- Uh-
好吧   回见
All right. See you later.
我不知道  好吧  我认为这很正式
I don't know, man. I think it's official.
我爱上 Summer 了   我爱她的笑
I'm in love with Summer. I love her smile.
爱她的头发  爱她的膝盖
I love her hair. I love her knees.
爱她脖子上心型的胎记
I love this heart-shaped birthmark she has on her neck.
爱她时不时说话前舔一下嘴唇
I love the way she sometimes licks her lips before she talks.
爱听她笑
I love the sound of her laugh.
爱她睡觉时的样子
I love the way she looks when she's sleeping.
♪ She's like the wind ♪
爱每次听到这首歌的时候就想起她
I love how I hear this song every every time I think of her.
爱她给我的感觉
I love how she makes me feel.
就像-
Like-
就像什么都有可能  或者 -  我不知道 像 -
Like anything's possible, or like- I don't know. Like-
生命的意义
Like life is worth it.
这不是什么好事
This is not good.
她喜欢马格利特和霍普 [画家]
She likes Magritte and Hopper.
我们聊了《战栗杀机》20分钟
And we talked about Banana fish for like 20 minutes.
我们很合适  真疯狂
We're so compatible, it's insane.
她- 好吧  她一点都不像我想的   她很迷人
She's- well, she's not like I thought at all. She's amazing.
- Oh 孩子  - 什么
Oh, boy. What?
人家跟你有同样奇怪的癖好
Just 'cause some cute girl likes the same bizarro crap you do,
并不代表就是你的精神伴侣  汤姆
that doesn't make her your soul mate, Tom.
红队胜！  - 你说什么
Red team wins! - What do you mean?
- 完蛋了  - 什么
- It's off. - What?
- 我和Summer  - 曾经好过吗
- Me and Summer. - Was it ever on?
没有 但是如果走运的话  还有可能
No, but it could have been, in a world where good things happen to me.
- 对 可现在不是  - 对
- Yeah, well, that's not really where we live. - No.
帅气
Lucky.
那么 发生了什么
So, what happened?
你们准备好了   恩
All right. You ready? Yeah.
这样  还差九层的时候  就我们俩
So there we are. Nine more floors to ride, just me and her.
Hey, Summer.
Hey  Summer
Hi
Hi.
周末过的怎么样
How was your weekend?
棒极了
It was good.
你相信吗
Can you believe that shit?
等等  相信什么
I'm sorry. What shit?
- 我听漏什么了  - 她竟然说 棒极了 "极" 加了重音
- I think I missed something. - She said, "It was good." Emphasis on the "good."
她的意思是说  她整个周末都在健身房和某个小子做爱
She basically said she spent the weekend having sex with some guy she met at the gym.
- 无语凝噎  - 管他呢 我放弃了
Skank. Whatever. I'm over it.
- 你丫到底怎么了  - 她对我没兴趣
What the hell is wrong with you? She's not interested in me.
我无能为力了
There's really nothing I can do about that.
- 只是因为她说 棒极了  - 还有其他事
Just because she said it was good? And some other things.
就像她说.. 恩.. "你好" 而不是 "嗨"
Like, did she say, uh, "hey" instead of "hi"?
我是说  你就知道她是女同了  对吧
I mean, 'cause you know that that- that means that she's a lesbian, right?
我给了她很多机会
I gave her plenty of chances.
我要去库房  你们谁要带点东西
I'm going to the supply room. Do you guys need anything?
我觉得你知道我要什么
I think you know what I need.
呃.. 墨盒
Uh, toner.
好的  没问题
Okay. Sure. No problem.
♪ Good times for a change ♪
♪ See, the luck I've had ♪
♪ Can make a good man turn bad ♪
♪ So, please, please, please ♪
♪ Let me, let me, let me ♪
♪ Let me get what I want ♪
现在好了 不管怎样  我不想了  我只是.. 你知道
Whatever, man. It's fine. I don't need this crap really. I just, you know-
我很平静 很淡定
I'm comfortable. I'm unhassled.
人们没发现  但寂寞...
People don't realize this, but loneliness-
- 很淡定  - 你可以约她
- It's underrated. - You could just ask her out.
别傻了
Don't be stupid.
噢
Hey.
- 今天周五  去唱歌吧  - 不去
This Friday, all you can karaoke at the Mill. No.
- 别  - 上次那事以后 他们不会让你进店了
Come on. They're not gonna let you back in there after last time.
呃.. 没那么糟吧
Ah, I wasn't that bad.
哥们 你吐到台上 差点跟酒保打起来...
Dude, you threw up on the stage, you tried to fight the bartender...
你还威胁要烧了那家店
and you threatened to burn the place down.
- 但我没有真的烧了它  - 我们不会再去了  哥们
But I didn't burn the place down. We're not going back there, man.
不是那样  好吧 这是工作 所有办公室的人都要去
Look. It's not like that, okay? It's a work thing. The whole office is going.
- 我不去 哪怕...  - 认真听我说
I can't go, even if I wanted- You're not listening to me.
- 什么  - "所有"办公室的人都要去
What? The whole office is going.
♪ Just like every cowboy ♪
♪ Sings a sad, sad song ♪
♪ Every rose has its thorn ♪
- 嗨  - 嗨
Hi. Hi.
- 他们说你不来了  - 你过我...
They said you weren't coming. You asked if I was-
这歌太棒了
Goddamn. That song is brilliant!
- 怎么了 Hansen  - Summer Summer
What's up, Hansen? Summer. Summer
- 该我了  - 快上来
That's me. Come on up.
你
You
- 我是菜鸟  别笑我  - 哇！
Okay. I'm new, so no making fun of me. Whoo!
多谢  头儿
Thanks, chief.
- 哦 谢了  - 干杯
Ah, thanks. Yeah, man.
干杯
Cheers.
♪ I got some troubles but they won't last ♪
♪ I'm gonna lay right down here in the grass ♪
♪ And pretty soon all my troubles will pass ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm in Su-Su-Su ♪
♪ Su-Su-Su ♪
♪ Su-Su-Su-Su-Su-Su ♪
♪ Sugar Town ♪
- 以前是  - 我猜的
Like, that's what I was- I guess.
- 嗨  -嘿
Hello. Hi.
我..呃.. 我不知道你要加入我们
I didn't, uh- I didn't know you were gonna join us.
我应该给你拿... 拿一瓶--  或者--
I would have gotten you, you know, a drink, or-
- 已经有了  - 恩
I'm good. You're good?
你 你很棒 太棒了  唱的   - 谢了
You- You were great- great up, uh, singing. Thank you.
我本来想唱 "生来奔波" 可他们这没
I wanted to sing "Born To Run," but they didn't have it.
- 我喜欢 "生来奔波"  - 我也是
I love "Born To Run." Me too.
- Tom 是新泽西人  - 是吗
Tom's from New Jersey. Really?
恩  我在那长大  12岁才离开
Yeah. I grew up there. Uh, I lived there till I was 12.
我的猫就姓斯普林斯丁
I named my cat after Springsteen.
- 别开玩笑了 那它叫什么
No kidding. What-what was his name?
布鲁斯
Bruce.
哦  很形象
Oh. That makes sense.
那么  你有男朋友吗
So, do you have a boyfriend?
- 没有  - 为什么不找个
- No. - Why not?
- 因为不想  - 别逗了 我不信
- 'Cause I don't want one.  - Come on. I don't believe that.
你不相信一个女人想自由独立
You don't believe that a woman could enjoy being free and independent?
你是女同
Are you a lesbian?
不 我不是
No, I'm not a lesbian.
我只是感觉不舒服  作谁的女朋友的话
I just don't feel comfortable being anyone's girlfriend.
我不想是任何人的任何人
I don't actually feel comfortable being anyone's anything, you know.
- 我不知道你在说什么   - 是吗
- I don't know what you're talking about. - Really?
不明白
Nope.
好吧  那我 "说来话长" 了
Okay. Let me break it down for you.
- 说嘛   - 我喜欢做我自己
- Break it down. - Okay. I like being on my own.
关系太复杂  人们觉得受伤
Relationships are messy, and people's feelings get hurt.
谁希望这样  我们还年轻
Who needs it? We're young.
我们住在这世上最漂亮的城市
We live in one of the most beautiful cities in the world.
为什么不开心点
Might as well have fun while we can and...
把那些严肃的问题先扔一边
save the serious stuff for later.
操蛋  你是个花花公子  她真花心
Holy shit. You're a dude. She's a dude.
好好  等一下  如果你恋爱了怎么办
Okay. But wait, wait. What happens if you fall in love?
什么
What?
你不会相信那些吧
Well, you don't believe that, do you?
是爱  不是圣诞老人
It's love. It's not Santa Claus.
好吧  那个字代表什么
Well, what does that word even mean?
我有过那种关系  但我不觉得我见过
I've been in relationships, and I don't think I've ever seen it.
- 好吧  可能...  - 大多数婚姻中途就完蛋了
Well, maybe that's- And most marriages end in divorce these days.
- 就像我父母   - 我也是  但...
Like my parents. Okay. Mine too, but-
我认为这个花心的女人太武断了
Me thinks the lady doth protest too much.
这个花心的女人没有
The lady dothn't.
没爱情这回事  那是童话
There's no such thing as love. It's a fantasy.
我认为不对
Well, I think you're wrong.
好的  那么
Okay. Well,
我漏了什么
what is it that I'm missing then?
当你感觉到爱的时候你就明白了
I think you know it when you feel it.
求同存异吧
I guess we can just agree to disagree.
好吧
Yeah.
那么 下一个谁来
- Okay. Who's singing next?
我推荐这位少年维特
I nominate Young werther here.
- 我还没有喝到...  - 酒保
I'm not nearly drunk enough to- Bartender.
♪ Outside there's a boxcar waiting ♪
♪ Outside the family stew ♪
♪ out by the fire breathing ♪
♪ Outside we wait till our face turns blue ♪
♪ I know the nervous walking ♪
♪ I know the dirty beard ha-ha-hangs ♪
♪ Out by the box car waiting ♪
♪ Take me away to nowhere plains ♪
♪ There is a wait so long   So long, so long ♪
♪ There is a wait so long ♪
♪ Here comes your man ♪
棒极了
whoo! You're good!
♪ Here comes your man ♪
是...
Is it-
♪ Here comes your man ♪
- 不是吗  - 不是
It's not? No, that's not it.
- 那是什么   - 我不知道  恩 ..
What is that then? I don't know. That-
什么来着  不对  我知道
That- That's something, but that's not it. I know.
- 我以前每周都看  - 哦 对
Ah, I used to watch it every week. Oh. Yeah!
- 那是最好的电视节目  - 我知道
It was the best show on TV. I know.
霹雳游侠  对吧  主题曲太棒了
Knight Rider? Come on. And the theme song is really good.
- 太棒了   - 我惦记了一周
So good. This is gonna bother me for a week.
我也是
Me too.
♪ And I'm proud to be an American ♪
♪ Where at least I know I'm free ♪
♪ And I'd like to entertain- ♪
- 你太棒了  - 我知道  哥们
- You were amazing. I know, buddy.
你太棒了
You're amazing.
太高兴了
This was so much fun. Yeah.
你们太.. 等 等一下 嗨
You guys are so much- Wait! Wait! Hey.
- 什么   - 不是你
What's up? Not you.
你
You.
- 他喜欢你  - 好了
He likes you. Okay.
- 他喜欢你  - 晚安 肯德基
He likes likes you! Good night, McKenzie.
- Tom 你为什么不告诉她  - 好了
Why don't you just tell her, Tom? Yeah.
- 你那么棒  - 抱歉  你看到了 他..
You guys are the best! Sorry you had to see that. He's-
- 每次都这样  他 .. 可能..
Happens every time we come here. He, uh- I don't know.
他唱的什么吧
Something about that guy and singing.
- 真的吗   - 对 对
Is that true? Yeah, yeah.
他喝醉了  唱歌  醉得一塌糊涂
He drinks, and he sings and just loses his shit.
不  不是麦肯奇
No, uh, not McKenzie.
另一件事
Um, the other thing.
什么
What thing?
你.. 喜欢我
Do you... like me?
对
Yeah.
对  当然 我喜欢你
Yeah, of course I like you.
朋友那种
As friends?
对  朋友
Right. As friends.
只是朋友那样
Just as friends?
我的意思是 ... 呃 ...  我没认真想过... 呃 ...
Yeah. I mean, l- I don't know. I hadn't really thought about, um-
对  怎么了
Yes. Why?
没什么   我只是
No reason. I just-
觉得你很有趣   我倒是很想跟你做朋友
I think you are interesting, and I'd like for us to be friends.
可以吗
Is that all right?
当然  那么...呃...
Yeah. It's, um-
对  你和我  我们应该成为朋友   嗯
Yeah. You and me. We should be friends. Mmm.
恩  好的
Okay. Good.
那么   我走这边
Well, I'm that way, so-
- 好吧  晚安   - 晚安
Okay. Well, good night. Good night.
- 嗨   - 嘿
- Hey. - Hi.
那 .. 那天很开心...
So, that was fun the other night.
- 你丫个混蛋  - 嘘
You son of a bitch. Shh!
- 几周啦  怎么还对那妞还念念不忘  - 我没有
The same girl you've been obsessing over for weeks now? I've not been obsessing.
你不是说过高攀不上 100万年也搞不定的
The girl you said was out of your league, that you'd never have a chance with.
- 那妞  - 保罗  安静点
That girl. Paul, seriously.
- 你上她了  - 没有
Did you bang her? No.
- 什么 口交 手淫   - 没  老大
What, hum job? Hand job? Man, no.
没有  还早着呢   我们..我们接吻了
No jobs. I'm still unemployed. We- We kissed.
跟哥说实话 我是你最好的朋友
Level with me, man. Come on. This is your best friend, huh?
都听你絮絮叨叨好几周啦
Your best friend who tolerated you whining about this girl for weeks on end.
- 保罗  - 你根本就是盯梢她
Paul- You were essentially stalking her!
保罗  闭嘴
- Paul! Shh!
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi. - Hey.
- 我是Summer  - Summer
I'm Summer. Summer.
- 我是保罗  - 嗨 保罗  很高兴见到你
I'm Paul. Hi, Paul. Nice to meet you.
好吧   我该走了  我还有些事  饭还在锅上
Well, I gotta go. I gotta do some, you know.
- 对  哥们  - 呃.. 当我没来过
Yeah, man. Um, pretend I was never here.
哦  等 等一下  Tom  呃... 如果有什么...
Oh, wait! Tom, Tom, Tom, Tom. Um, if any jobs come up-
谢了  保罗  回见
Thanks, Paul! See ya!
他.. 呃 老朋友了
He's, uh, you know, an old friend.
如果你听到...
If you heard any of, um-
- 听到什么  - 没什么  你要走了吗
Heard what? Nothing. You wanna go?
对  我在盯梢   我在盯梢
Yeah. I'm stalking. I mean, I'm starving.
哦 亲爱的
Ah, hon?
我们的水池坏了
Our sink is broken.
所有的都坏了
Man, all of our sinks are broken.
找什么
What are we looking for again?
- 三角架   - 买个台灯吧
Uh, trivets. How 'bout a fly gel?
不  算了吧
No, I don't think so.
是吗  你不想买个台灯
No? You don't want a fly gel?
家  温暖的家
Home sweet home.
咱们家可真好  是吧
Our place really is lovely, isn't it?
恩
Yes.
哦 "美国偶像" 开演了
Ooh! Idol's on.
电视坏了
The TV's not working.
哦
Oh.
好吧  我饿死了
Well, I'm famished.
吃点东西去
Let's eat.
嗯~ 真好闻
Mmm. Smells delicious.
哦  亲爱的  它真的很好吃
Oh, honey, that's because it is delicious.
我自己做的
I made it myself.
- 贝果[硬面包圈]  - 你的最爱
Bald eagle. Your favorite.
恩
Mm-hmm.
水池坏了
The sink's broken.
没事  因为 ..
Well, that's okay, because...
就是为什么  我们有两个厨房
that's why we bought a home with two kitchens.
你真聪明
You're so smart.
看谁先到卧室
I'll race you to the bedroom.
♪ Left behind ♪
♪ There goes the fear again ♪
♪ Let it go ♪
♪ There goes the fear♪
亲爱的  我怎么跟你说
Darling, I don't know how to tell you this,
可是... 那些中国人在咱们浴室
but... there's a Chinese family in our bathroom.
真好
This is fun.
你真好
You're fun.
谢谢
Thanks.
嗨  呃
Hey, um,
我想跟你说
I just wanna tell you that, um,
我不是...
I'm not really looking...
认真的
for anything... serious.
这样好吗
Is that okay?
没事
Yeah.
大多数人听到这个都很崩溃
'Cause some people kind of freak out when they hear that.
我不会
No, not me.
真的吗
You sure?
就像暧昧  对吧  慢慢来
Yeah. Like, casual. Right? Take it slow.
对
Right.
没压力
No pressure.
等等... 你能等一下吗
Can you, uh- Can you wait one second?
冷静点  她是个女孩
Okay. Settle. She's just a girl.
女孩
Just a girl.
她想保持暧昧
She wants to keep it casual,
她现在在我床上
which is why she's in my bed right now.
但是暧昧... 那正是暧昧的人该做的
But that's casual. That's what casual people do.
好吧  没事
That's fine. That's great.
- 嗨  - 嗨
Hi. Hi.
♪ What I want you've got and it might be hard to handle ♪
♪ Like the flame that burns the candle ♪
♪ The candle feeds the flame ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah what I've got full stock ♪
♪ of thoughts and dreams that scatter♪
♪ You're pullin' them all together ♪
♪ And I can't explain oh, yeah ♪
♪ Well, well, you ♪
嗨
Hey.
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh, ooh-ooh ♪
你好
Hello.
♪ You make my dreams come true ♪
嗨
Hi.
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh, ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh   well, well, well, you ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh, ooh-ooh   oh, yeah ♪
谢谢
Thanks.
♪ You make my dreams come true ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh, you, ooh-ooh  Yeah, oh, yeah ♪
♪ You ♪
♪ on a night when bad dreams become a screamer♪
♪ when they're messin' with the dreamer ♪
♪ I can laugh it in the face ♪
♪ Twist and shout my way out ♪
♪ And wrap yourself around me ♪
♪ 'Cause I ain't the way you found me ♪
♪ And I'll never be the same oh, yeah ♪
♪ Well, well, you ♪
♪ You make my dreams come true ♪
♪ ooh-ooh, you, ooh-ooh    whoa, yeah ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh  well, well, well, you ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh, ooh-ooh  Whoo-whoo ♪
♪ You make my dreams come true ♪
♪ ooh-ooh, you, ooh-ooh ♪
♪ oh-oh-oh, yeah  Ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Now listen to this ♪
♪ I'm down on my daydream ♪
♪ oh, that sleepwalk should be over by now ♪
♪ Oh, no ♪
♪ Yeah, you ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
给我... 给我 阿弗雷多的号码
You know, I'm gonna- I'm gonna- I'm gonna get Alfredo's number.
好的  过会给你
Okay. And I'll- And I'll bring it to you.
- 行吗  - 没问题
Okay. Okay?
这个是单人纸牌吗
Is this Solitaire?
她回心转意了还是其他什么
So, did you get her back yet or what?
继续工作吧
Working on it.
- 也许你该写本书  - 什么
Hey, maybe you should write a book. What?
亨利·米勒说过  忘掉一个女人的最好方法...
Well, you know, Henry Miller said the best way to get over a woman...
就是把她变成文学
is to turn her into literature.
那他做的爱肯定比我多
Well, that guy had a lot more sex than me.
哇  就是这个  就是这个
Oh, this is it! This is it!
很高兴收到你的邮件
So great to hear from you.
但是这周不行  要不下周
I can't this week, but maybe next?
我希望这代表着  你已经准备好做朋友了
I hope this means you're ready to be friends.
对  就是这个
Yeah, that's it. That is it.
你的妞疯了
Your girl is losing it.
你就不能稍微认真一下吗
Can you just be serious, for just a second?
- 我很认真  - 不  你一点也不
I am being totally serious. No, you're joking around.
- 我没有   -“章鱼花园”
No, I am not joking around. "Octopus's Garden"?
“章鱼花园” 是披头士发行的最好的歌
Yes, "octopus's Garden" is the best Beatles song ever recorded.
你怎么不说是 “猪猡”
Why don't you just say "Piggies"?
别闹了  我喜欢 林戈·斯塔尔
Come on. I love Ringo Starr!
- 没人喜欢 林戈·斯塔尔  - 那正是我喜欢他的原因
Nobody loves Ringo Starr. That's what I love about him.
不  不
No, no.
哇  看起来不错
Ooh, this looks good.
评价很高
Gets really good reviews.
你知道吗   看起来太难以置信了
You know what? That looks pretty doable.
- 你这时候要我干嘛   - 这是你的主意
Why are you asking me now? Because this was your idea.
- 手放这  - 等一下
Put your hand there. Wait one second.
好了  三 二 一
Okay. Three, two, one! One.
逛街可能没那么好玩  可如果...
Yeah, the street level isn't so exciting, but-
你抬头看
Like, if you look up-
♪ Sweet ♪
♪ Disposition ♪
艺术品
The Fine Arts Building.
这栋楼的设计师   沃克和艾森   我最喜欢的两个
The guys who designed this, Walker and Eisen, are... two of my favorites.
很帅吧
Isn't that cool?
♪ Never ♪
♪ Too soon ♪
- 这是我最喜欢的地方  - 这吗
This is my favorite spot. This is?
这是你最喜欢的地方
This is your favorite spot?
就是这
Right here.
怎么说
How come?
我不知道  很难解释 感觉
Uh, I don't know. It's kind of hard to explain, I guess.
说说嘛
Well, try.
好吧
Um- Well, okay.
就像  那座建筑
Like, that building- that's, uh-
它 1911 年就在那了
That's been there since 1911.
还有那座大陆风的建筑  是洛杉矶最早的摩天大楼
And that- that's the Continental. That's L.A.'s first skyscraper.
1904 年建成的
It was built in 1904.
那栋呢
What is that?
那个
That?
- 那个是停车场   - 噢
That's a parking lot. Oh!
那些  还有那些 全是
Yeah. That's- That's also a parking lot.
那些
That's, um- Yeah.
还有很多漂亮的建筑  虽然...
There's a lot of beautiful stuff here too though.
我只是... 我只是希望人们更多的注意到
I don't know. I just... wish people would notice it more.
如果是我
If it were me, then, uh-
如果你什么
If it were you what?
我是说... 如果是我的话  我会让人们注意到吧
I don't know. I think I'd... make 'em notice.
你怎么引起他们的注意
How would you make them notice?
我不知道  太多要做的了
I don't know. There's a lot of different stuff you could do.
给我看看
Show me.
拜托 我对建筑不是很懂
Please. I don't know anything about architecture.
- 你想让我画出来   - 对
You want me to draw you something? Yeah.
- 可没带纸  - 用我的胳膊吧
I don't have any paper. Well, use my arm.
求你了  我想要个纹身
Please, I need a tattoo.
- 让我们看看你的胳膊  -多有灵感
Well, let's see your arm. That's the spirit.
要把建筑描绘得更精确一些  所以
Well, the buildings need to be integrated better, so-
可以把轮廓画大一些
You could maximize light capacity here.
有点乱
It's kind of messy.
没事
That's okay.
对于 Tom Hansen   从这个晚上开始 一切都变了
For Tom Hansen, this was the night where everything changed.
那堵 Summer 用来躲避的墙
That wall Summer so often hid behind-
那堵  关于距离 关于空间  关于暧昧
the wall of distance, of space, of casual-
那堵墙正在慢慢倒塌
that wall was slowly coming down.
是 Tom  进入了她的世界
For here was Tom, in her world,
一个很少人可以进入的世界
a place few had been invited to see with their own eyes.
Summer 希望他进来
And here was Summer, wanting him there.
他 而不是别人
Him, no one else.
- 你见过龙卷风吗   - 没有
Have you ever been in a tornado? No.
我牙掉下来过
It's that and my teeth falling out.
- 我也是  - 是吗
I have that too! You do?
恩  真怪异  好像我老了
Yeah! It's so weird. It's like being an old man.
你还经历过什么
What else do you have?
呃  地震
Um, earthquakes?
- 真的 - 假的
Really? No.
我曾经做过一个梦 我在飞
You know, I dream sometimes about flying.
开始的时候我只是跑   那么快
It starts out like I'm running really, really fast.
就像 超人
I'm, like, superhuman.
渐渐地面变成了陡峭的岩石
And the terrain starts to get really rocky and steep.
我跑的太快了  离开了地面
And then I'm running so fast that my feet aren't even touching the ground.
我飞起来了  很奇妙  奇妙且真实
And I'm floating, and it's like this amazing, amazing realness.
感觉很自由  很安全
I'm free. I'm safe.
然后我明白了
Then I realize,
我是一个人
l'm completely alone.
然后就醒了
And then I wake up.
他听着  Tom 开始发觉
As he listened, Tom began to realize...
这并不是随便讲给人听的故事
that these weren't stories routinely told.
而是有资格的人才能听的
These were stories one had to earn.
他感觉到那堵墙正在消失
He could feel the wall coming down.
他很好奇有没有其他人也曾到这里
He wondered if anyone else had made it this far.
而后面的话  改变了一切
Which is why the next six words changed everything.
我以前从没跟别人讲过这些
I've never told anybody that before.
我猜我不是 别人
I guess I'm not just anybody.
那你现在是什么
- So what are you exactly?
- 我不知道  - 男朋友
I don't know. Are you her boyfriend?
- 很显然不是   - 对
It's not that simple. Sure, it is.
就像  你们恋爱了吗  拜托
What, like, are we going steady? Come on, guys.
我们.. 我们是成年人   你知道我们在想什么
You know, we're- we're adults. We know how we feel.
我们不用贴那些标签
We don't need to put labels on it.
就像 "男朋友"  "女朋友"
I mean, "boyfriend," "girlfriend."
那些东西都... 太幼稚了
All that stuff is- It's really juvenile.
- 听起来好像你是同性恋   - 确实
You sound gay. You really do.
好吧  首先
Okay, first of all,
你最后一个女朋友是  七年级的艾米·苏斯曼
your last girlfriend was Amy Sussman in the seventh grade,
跟你约会  大概才三个小时吧
and you dated for, like, three hours.
而你  你和瑞比从... 1998 年开始的吧
And you- you've been with Robyn since what- like 1998?
- 97年   - 对  97年
'97. '97. See-
射击
Shoot.
我觉得你们俩不是  现代爱情方面的专家
I don't think the two of you are exactly authorities on modern relationships.
- 那我该怎么办   - 你该去问她
So, what should I do? You should ask her.
怎么了
What?
我在想  干吗要自找麻烦
Well, why rock the boat, is what I'm thinking.
一切不都很好吗
I mean, things are going well.
你想确定关系  但那可能就完蛋了
You start putting labels on it, that's like the kiss of death.
- 就像 " 我爱你 "    - 好了 我知道你说什么了
It's like saying, "I love you." Yeah, I know what you mean.
我和肖恩也是那样
That's what happened between me and Sean.
- 哪的混蛋肖恩   - 马克之前的男朋友
Who the hell's Sean? My boyfriend before Mark.
谁是... 算了
Who the- Never mind.
- 那么  你的意思是   - 我是说你确实想问她
So, what you're saying- I'm saying you do want to ask her.
很明显   你只是怕答案不是你想要的
It's obvious. You're just afraid you'll get an answer you don't want,
那会打碎几个月以来所有的幻想
which will shatter all the illusions of how great these past few months have been.
这样   如果是我
Now look, if it were me,
我会现在就弄清楚  而不是稀里糊涂地回到家
I'd find out now before you show up at her place...
发现她和挪威来的拉尔斯躺在一起
and, well, she's in bed with Lars from Norway.
挪威来的拉尔斯
Who's Lars from Norway?
也许是她在健身房遇到的
Just some guy she met at the gym...
有着布拉德·皮特俏脸和耶稣魅力的人
with Brad Pitt's face and Jesus' abs.
等等  不  我们不能这样结束
Wait! No, Coach. We're not done here.
- 雷切尔  - 这很容易 Tom
Rachel! Look, it's easy, Tom.
别跟个小姑娘似的
Just don't be a pussy.
你还好吧
You okay?
- 恩   - 是吗
Yeah. You sure?
Summer  我得问你点事
Summer, I gotta ask you something.
- 什么   - 我们...
What? What are we, um-
- 我们在干嘛    - 我们不是要去看电影吗
What are we doing? I thought we were going to the movies.
对  我的意思是  我们...
Yeah. Nah, I mean, like, what are we, like-
我们算什么
What's going on here, with us?
我不知道
I don't know.
有什么关系
Who cares?
- 我很开心 你不也是吗   - 开心
I'm happy. Aren't you happy? Yeah.
对啊
Good.
伦敦 1964
London, 1964.
那些女孩知道怎么打扮
Those girls knew how to dress.
可今天  到处都是墨镜和
Nowadays, it's all these giant sunglasses...
纹身
and tattoos.
手提包里放着小狗
It's handbags with little dogs in them.
- 谁允许的   - 有人喜欢
Who okayed this? Some people like it.
我喜欢你的打扮
I like how you dress.
我考虑过 在我脚上刺个蝴蝶
I was thinking about getting a butterfly tattoo about yea big on my ankle.
别
No.
哦
Oh.
嗨
Yo.
怎么样
How's it going?
还行
Uh, okay.
你住附近
You live around here?
对 不是很远
Um, yeah, not too far.
我从来没过你
I've never seen you here before.
你不是很善于观察
You're not too observant.
很好笑  你很幽默
That's funny. You're funny.
- 请你喝一杯   - 算了 谢谢
So let me buy you a drink. No, thank you.
- 你在和他约会   - 嗨 我叫 Tom
You with this guy? Hey, I'm Tom.
随便  来吧  请你喝一杯   你喝什么
Whatever. So, come on. One drink. What are you drinking?
我说了算了  谢谢
I said no, thanks.
- 你还挺认真  这小子
You're serious? This guy?
- 嗨 哥们...  - 你想干嘛  别那么野蛮
Hey, buddy- You know what? Don't be rude.
我在敷衍你   我没兴趣
I'm flattered, but I'm not interested.
你为什么离我们远点   谢谢你了
So why don't you go over there and leave us alone? Thanks.
这是自由的国家
It's a free country.
不敢相信他是你男朋友
I can't believe this is your boyfriend.
你干嘛
What are you doing?
这真疯狂
It was really just a crazy thing.
它.. 发生的太快了 但是..
It happened like- It felt like it happened fast, but really,
感觉好像很慢
it- it also felt like it was happening really slowly,
身边的一切都...
like everything all was just-
很难表达  就像... 你理解不了
I don't know. It doesn't feel like you think it would-
嗨  你怎么了
Hey, what's the matter?
我只是.. 我无法相信你
I just- I can't believe you.
你无法相信我
You can't believe me?
你很 非常 不冷静
You were so completely, completely uncool in there.
等等  你生我气了   我是在保护你
Wait. Are you mad at me? I just got my ass kicked for you.
是吗  是为我吗  保护我
Oh, really? Was that for me? Was that for my benefit?
是的
Yes, it was.
好吧  那下次别这样做  我不需要你帮忙
Okay, well, next time don't, 'cause I don't need your help.
你知道吗  我很累
You know what? I'm really tired.
我们能明天再谈吗
Can we talk about this tomorrow?
不  知道什么
No. You know what?
我哪都不去  除非你告诉我怎么了
I'm not going anywhere till you tell me what's going on.
没什么
Nothing's going on.
我们只是...
We're just...
什么  我们只是什么
What? We're just what?
- 我们只是朋友   - 别拿这个当借口
We're just friends. No! Don't pull that with me!
想都别想
Don't even try to.
你不是这样对你朋友的
This is not how you treat your friend.
在打印室里接吻  牵着手逛家居
Kissing in the copy room? Holding hands in IKEA?
鸳鸯浴  算了吧  朋友  真是蛋疼
Shower sex? Come on! Friends, my balls!
我喜欢你 Tom  我只是不想恋爱
I like you, Tom. I just don't want a relationship
你不是唯一有发言权的
well, you're not the only one that gets a say in this!
我也有  我说 我们是一对  操蛋
I do too! And I say we're a couple, goddamn it!
先请
After you, please.
我不该那样
I shouldn't have done that.
- 不该什么  - 生你的气
Done what? Gotten mad at you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
好吧  我们不需要贴上标签
Look, we don't have to put a label on it.
这很好  我明白了
That's fine. I get it.
但你知道  我只是.. 需要点默契
But, you know, I just- I need some consistency.
我知道
I know.
我只是想弄清楚  你不会一天早上醒来
I need to know that you're not gonna wake up in the morning...
感觉.. 不一样
and... feel differently.
但我不能给你保证
And I can't give you that.
没人能
Nobody can.
很抱歉 让你伤心了
That hurt? I'm sorry.
没事
No, it doesn't hurt.
我喜欢你
I like you.
没事了
All right.
♪ You loved her You were kissing ♪
那么  你呢   有过男朋友吗
Shh. Well, what about you? Did you ever even have a boyfriend?
- 当然  - 恩
Well, of course. Yeah?
- 恩  - 跟我讲讲
Yeah. Well, tell me about them.
- 不   - 为什么
No. Oh? Why not?
因为那不重要
Because it's not important.
我想听
I'm interested.
好吧   你想听
All right. Fine. You want to go there?
我能接受
Yeah. I can take it. Fine.
那么
So-
高中时的男朋友叫马库斯
Well, in high school there was Markus.
四分卫  肩带  返校节国王
- Quarterback-slash-homecoming king?
不 他是个赛艇运动员
No. He was a rower.
他很性感
He was very hot.
大学里有一阵子  和查理在一起
For a brief time in college there was, um- there was Charlie.
她 人很好 但是...
She was nice, but-
之后是我在锡耶纳的那个学期
And then there was my semester in Sienna.
和费尔南多·波拉戴尔在一起
Fernando Belardelli.
他绰号叫 "美洲狮"
Also known as "The Puma."
- 美洲狮   - 对 美洲狮   因为...
- The Puma? - Yeah, The Puma, 'cause, you know.
那么
So-
- 就这些吗   - 相处过一段时间的就这些
Oh, that's it? The ones that lasted, yeah.
然后呢   为什么..  他们为什么出局了
What happened? Why- Why didn't they work out?
世事难料  人生就是这样
What always happens. Life.
这是我听过的 最白痴的事
That's the dumbest thing I've ever heard.
肯定不是  那很了不起   相信我
No, it's not. It's awesome. Trust me.
我说真的
I'm serious.
我先来
I'll go first.
鸡巴
Penis.
- 鸡巴   - 鸡巴
Penis! Penis!
- 鸡巴   - 孩子们在附近
Penis! There's kids around.
没有
There are no kids around.
- 鸡巴  - 鸡巴
Penis! Penis!
- 很好玩   - 对
You having fun? Yeah.
你和美洲狮也玩这个
This is the kind of thing you did with The Puma, isn't it?
不 我们很少出门
Oh, we rarely left the room.
鸡巴
Penis!
- 抱歉  妥瑞氏症  你们知道的  - 鸡巴
Sorry. Tourette's. You know how it is. Penis!
- 她也是   - 鸡巴   - 鸡巴
She has it too. Penis! Penis!
- 小声点  人们都在看你  - 好了 好了
Shh. Everyone's looking over here. I'm done. I'm done.
- 不喊了   - 恩
Are you done? I'm done.
- 真的   - 恩
You're done? Yeah.
- 太过分了  - 放开我吧 我不喊了
This is too much. Unleash me. I'm done.
- 保证  - 保证
Promise? I promise.
我保证
I promise.
鸡巴~
Penis!
- 很复杂  - 恩
It's very complex. Mmm.
某种程度上  有点像
In a way, it sort of, like,
表达.. 很多东西..
says... so much...
通过..
by...
很简单的东西
saying so little.
- 想去看电影吗   - 恩
Do you want to go to the movies? Yep.
他心碎了
Suffering.
很心碎
So much suffering.
心碎了  心碎了
Suffering. Suffering.
T-Tom
T-Tom?
万斯先生要你去他办公室见他
Mr. Vance would like to see you in his office.
Tom
Tom.
坐吧
Have a seat.
你最近怎么了
Has something happened to you recently?
什么意思
What do you mean?
家里某个人死了  还是生病了  之类的
A death in the family, someone taken ill- Anything like that.
没有
No.
我并不是在刺探你  可..
Look, I don't mean to pry, but...
和 Summer 的离开有关吗
does this have something to do with Summer leaving?
- 谁   - 我的助理
Who? My assistant.
- 你..   - Tom 大家都知道了
Your, um- Tom, everyone knows.
没关系
Never mind.
我找你来  是因为你的业绩
The reason I'm asking is, lately your work performance...
有点.. 下滑
has been... a little off.
- 等等  你说什么  - 好吧
I'm not following. Okay.
呃.. 这些是你上周写的
Um, here's something that you wrote last week.
恩.. " 玫瑰是红色的  紫罗兰是蓝色
Uh, "Roses are red, violets are blue.
滚一边去  混蛋 "
Fuck you, whore."
现在很多商店都在为情人节做准备..
Now, most shoppers at Valentine's Day-
- 万斯先生 你要解雇我吗   - 不  不
Mr. Vance, are you firing me? No. No.
放松点 Hansen  你是我见过的最好的一个
Relax, Hansen. You're one of the good ones.
恩  呃  抱歉
Okay. Uh, yeah, I'm sorry.
有点复杂
Things have been a little difficult.
没事  我很清楚这一切
That's okay. I completely understand that.
我觉得你应该把你的状态引导到..
I'm just saying that perhaps you could channel those energies,
引导到类似的事情上
um, into something like this.
葬礼和吊唁
Funerals and sympathy.
痛苦  悲伤  失去信心
Misery, sadness, loss of faith,
活不下去
no reason to live.
很适合你
This is perfect for you.
- 呃..  - 很好
Uh- Good. Okay.
- 继续工作吧
Now back to work you go.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 嗨   - 嗨
Hey. Hey.
- 你不是周五前要写20张卡片吗   - 全写完了
Don't you have, like, 20 cards to write by Friday? Nope. All done.
真的假的  能帮帮我吗  我已经用尽那些 " 恭喜 " 了
Really? Can you help me? 'Cause I've run out of ways to say "congrats."
我这里有 " 不错 "  " 好样的 "  " 干得好 "
Okay. I got "Good job," "Well done" and "Way to go."
就这些了
That's it.
" 你每天都让我感到骄傲
How 'bout, "Every day you make me proud,
但今天我送你张卡片 " 这个怎么样
but today you get a card."
- 操  真棒   - 当然
Shit, that's good! I know.
" 欢乐"  怎么样
Have you tried "Merry"?
哇  太棒了 欢乐  哇
Wow! That's perfect! Merry! Wow!
我们困在这一个小时了
We've been stuck on this for an hour.
恩.. 那么...
Hmm. How about...
" 我爱我们 "
"I love us"?
哇
Aw.
我恨 Summer
I hate Summer.
恨她的歪曲的牙齿
I hate her crooked teeth.
恨她60年代的发型
I hate her 1960s haircut.
恨她凹凸的膝盖
I hate her knobby knees.
恨她脖子上蟑螂似的污点
And I hate her cockroach-shaped splotch on her neck.
恨她说话前先舔下嘴唇
I hate the way she smacks her lips before she talks.
我恨她的笑
And I hate the way she sounds when she laughs.
♪ She's like the wind ♪
我恨这首歌
I hate this song!
孩子  你还是下车吧
Son, you're gonna have to exit the vehicle.
我通常不会相亲
I normally don't do blind dates,
但保罗和罗宾对你赞不绝口
but Paul and Robyn spoke very highly of you.
- 哦  - 他们说你写贺卡
Ah. They said you write greeting cards.
太有趣了  我也想写
That's so interesting. I wanted to write.
我大学是学英语的
I actually majored in English in college,
但你出来又能干嘛
but what are you gonna do with that degree?
- 我去了布朗  你去过哪   - 埃里森
I went to Brown. Where did you go? Alison.
恩
Hmm?
能认识你很高兴
Listen, it's great to meet you,
恩.. 你是个很有魅力的女孩
and... you're a very attractive girl.
我只是想事先说明 这不是...
I just wanted to say up front that this isn't-
这样不会有什么结果
It's not gonna go anywhere. Oh.
我曾喜欢过一个女孩   我爱她
I liked this girl. I mean, I loved her.
而她呢
What does she do?
她却扔我脸上坨屎
She took a giant shit on my face.
- 真事   - 真的假的
Literally. Literally?
- 假的   - 天哪 真扯淡
Not literally. That's disgusting. Jesus.
你怎么了
What's the matter with you?
重点是
The point is,
我纠结了  真的
I'm messed up. I am.
一方面  我想忘了她
You know, on the one hand, I want to forget her.
但另一方面
On the other hand,
我知道她是整个宇宙  唯一能让我快乐的人
I know that she's the only person in the entire universe that will make me happy.
- 恩   - 你曾经这样过吗
Mm-hmm. You ever do this?
不断回忆你们在一起的时光   一次又一次
You think back on the times you had with someone, replay it in your head over and over again,
找你们第一次出现问题
and you look for those first signs of trouble.
有两种解释
There's two options really.
一个是  她邪恶
Either... she's an evil,
没人性  卑鄙
emotionless, miserable human being,
或者   她是个机器人
or... she's a robot.
《机器娃娃》里的薇姬
Small Wonder. You know, Vicki.
- 这样一切都能解释了   - 我能问你个问题吗
That would explain a lot actually. Can I ask you a question?
- 好的   - 她劈过腿吗
Yeah. She never cheated on you?
- 没有    - 她利用你了吗
No. Never. She ever take advantage of you in any way?
没有
No.
她之前说她不想要男朋友  对吧
And she told you up front that she didn't want a boyfriend.
对
Yeah.
我明白了
I got a great idea.
♪ Well, some things you can explain away ♪
♪ But my heartache's in me every day ♪
♪ Did you stand by me No, not at all ♪
♪ Di- ♪
好吧  走吧   再见
Oh, fine! Go! That's fine. See ya.
浪费时间  你跟 Summer 差太远了
Waste of time. You don't look anything like Summer.
太平洋滑浪线二车道即将出发
Now departing on Track 2, Pacific Surfliner.
终点站是圣巴巴拉
Full service to Santa Barbara.
请您马上登车
All aboard, please.
- 嘿 小子   - 你在哪
Hey, baby. Hey, you here?
- 我没在   - 你什么意思  没在
Hell no. What do you mean, "Hell no"?
- 我不去了   - 是吗
I'm not going to that. Yes, you are.
哥们  那全是老人
No, man. It's gonna be all old people.
对  是你说你要去  我才来的
Yeah, but you said you were going. That's why I'm going.
所以昨晚给她打电话  说我病了
And that's why I called her last night, told her I was sick.
- 就像忍者   - 我&  我.. 我不会去那找马子的
Like a ninja. Dude! I'm gonna- I'm not gonna know anybody at this thing.
也许你能碰见个  性感小萝莉什么的
Maybe you'll meet some hot granddaughters or something.
- 我挂了    - 再见 哥们
I'm hanging up now. Bye, baby.
各位旅客请注意
May I have your attention, please?
乘至洛杉矶的旅客们
Passengers boarding the train in Los Angeles, please...
请您准备好车票以备出示
have your tickets out and ready for collection.
嗨  Tom
Hi, Tom!
嗨  Summer
Hey. Summer.
- 我刚才没注意到你   - 是吗
I must have walked right by you. Yeah.
你是要去哪  米莉家么
Well, um, what are you doing? Are you going to Millie's?
- 我也是   - 太好了
Me too. Cool.
- 我忘了你认识她    - 恩  我们一起工作...
- I forgot you knew her. - Yeah, we worked together all that time, so-
- 当然  - 我喜欢米莉  她很可爱
of course. I love Millie. She's the sweetest.
恩
She is.
- 你怎么样   - 不错
- How are you? - I'm good.
恩  我给你写信  但没收到过你的 ..
Good. L-I wrote to you. I never heard back, but-
哦  抱歉  我只是..
Yeah. Yeah. Sorry about that. L- I just, you know-
这些天过得一团糟  这放假了也不得休息  工作...
It got kind of crazy, and the holidays came up, so work was-
你还在万斯那儿干
You still working for Vance?
对
Yeah.
哦  我正要去喝杯咖啡 你 ..
Well, I was gonna go get a coffee if you wanna-
" 幸福建筑 "
"The Architecture of Happiness."
看起来很不错
Yeah. That looks like a good book.
恩 ..
Yeah, it's-
- 我不想打扰你   - 不 没事
Well, I don't want to bother you. No, no. I, um-
走吧  喝杯咖啡
Yeah, let's get coffee.
先
After you.
♪ Sweet ♪
♪ Disposition ♪
♪ Never ♪
♪ Too soon ♪
♪ A moment, a love A dream aloud ♪
♪ A kiss, a cry our rights, our wrongs ♪
- 你看起来很精神   - 谢谢
You look nice. Thanks.
你也是
So do you.
♪ Sweet ♪
走吧
well?
♪ Disposition ♪
鸡巴
Penis.
不
No.
现在我宣布你们结为夫妻
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
你可以吻新娘了
You may kiss the bride.
♪ Helping the kids out of their coats ♪
♪ Wait, the babies haven't been born ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh-oh-oh-oh, oh ♪
♪ Unpacking the bags and setting up ♪
♪ And planting lilacs and buttercups ♪
接下来呢
okay. What else you got?
- 你打呼噜   - 没有
Well, you snore. No, I don't.
- 当然有  - 我没有
You do. No, I don't.
好吧   你也打过
Yeah. Well, you do too.
- 当然    - 你脚还臭
Oh, I definitely do. And your feet reek.
- 就一次   - 每次都是
That one time! No, every time.
- 就那一天好吧   - 别狡辩了
That one time! No.
- 每天都是  那一次格外臭
That one time especially, but every time.
你起床的时候  头发都竖起来了
And when you wake up, your hair, it sticks up like that.
- 真好笑  - 你真恶趣味
It's ridiculous. You're ridiculous.
披头士里你最爱林戈
Your favorite Beatle is Ringo.
太对了
Damn right!
- 林戈最棒   - 林戈..
Ringo's the best. Ringo is-
笨蛋
Goose! Oh! Oh! Oh!
他太快了  算了
Man! He's fast. Damn! All right.
你抓到我了 我是鸭子
You got me. Duck.
鸭子
Duck.
♪ At last ♪
♪ My love has come along ♪
♪ My lonely days are over ♪
一  二  三
One, two, three.
♪ And life is like a song ♪
跳支舞吧
Wanna dance? Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
♪ Oh, at last ♪
我..
Hey, I was wondering, um-
♪ The skies above are blue ♪
周五我可能要开个派对
I was gonna maybe have a party on Friday, um,
在我家屋顶上  那个小花园
on our rooftop that has, like, a really nice garden,
那个  你来吗
if you want to come.
好吧
Yeah.
♪ For you are mine ♪
如果你不忙
If you're not busy.
应该不会
I don't think I will be.
♪ At last ♪
- 很不错 对吧   - 很棒
They're good, huh? They are good.
我想我人品爆发了
I guess I just got lucky.
我们从小学就认识了
Um, we met in elementary school.
七年级时我们课表都一样
In seventh grade we had the same class schedule,
怎么说呢
and, uh,
我们很合拍
we just clicked, you know?
爱情
Love?
该死  我可不太懂
Shit, I don't know.
只要她愿意  又可爱  对吧
As long as she's cute and she's willing, right?
其实可不可爱也无所谓
I'm flexible on the cute, so-
二十一年了
Twenty-one years.
她是指引我回家的明灯
She's the light that guides me home.
好吧  没错  是我引用贺卡上的话
Yes, that is from one of our cards.
不  别人写的
No. Someone else wrote it.
但说的很对
Doesn't make it less true.
我认为纯粹的 " 梦中女孩 "
I think technically the "girl of my dreams"...
要有.. 呃... 火辣的身材
would probably have, like, a really bodacious rack, you know.
与众不同的发型
Maybe different hair.
喜欢运动   的更好点
Probably- You know, she'd probably be a little more into sports.
但事实是
But, um, truthfully,
罗宾比我的梦中女孩还要好
Robyn's- Robyn's better than the girl of my dreams.
她真实
She's real.
♪ He never, ever saw it coming at all ♪
♪ Never, ever saw it coming at all ♪
Tom 去了她的公寓
Tom walked to her apartment,
沉醉在那晚的约定中
intoxicated by the promise of the evening.
他相信这次
He believed that this time...
期待会与现实并行
his expectations would align with reality.
♪ It's all right ♪
♪ Hey, open wide Here comes original sin ♪
- 嗨   - 嘿
Hi. Hey.
真帅
You look nice.
谢谢
Yeah. Thanks.
我喜欢你的领带
I like your tie. Wow! Hi.
- 最近好吗   - 还行  你呢
How you doing? Good. How are you?
不错
Good.
♪ It's all right It's all right, it's all right ♪
♪ It's all right ♪
这个是送你的
I, um, brought you something.
真漂亮
That's so nice.
谢谢
Thank you.
你太客气了   真不错
You shouldn't have. That's so nice. It's the-
太谢谢你了
Thank you so much. No problem.
我都迫不及待想读了
I'm excited to read it. Yeah.
咱们过去吧
Come on.
♪ And we're going to these meetings ♪
- Tom 你做什么工作的  - 我为贺卡撰写贺词
- So, Tom, what is it that you do? - Uh, I write greeting cards.
如果 Tom 愿意  他会是个很棒的建筑师
Tom could be a really great architect if he wanted to be.
真奇怪
That's unusual.
我是说  你怎么会放弃当建筑师
I mean, what made you go from one to the other?
我想
I guess I just figured,
与其做那些一次性的东西  比如建筑
why make something disposable, like a building,
不如做些永恒的东西  比如贺卡  你说呢
when you can make something that lasts forever, like a greeting card?
♪ It's all right It's all right ♪
什么
what?
你们认识吗
Do you guys know each other?
♪ No one's got it all ♪
♪ Power to the people We don't want it ♪
♪ we want pleasure And the TVs try to rape us ♪
♪ And I guess that they're succeeding ♪
♪ And we're going to these meetings ♪
♪ But we're not doing any meeting ♪
♪ And we're trying to be faithful ♪
♪ But we're cheating cheating, cheating ♪
♪ I'm the hero of the story Don't need to be saved ♪
♪ It's all right ♪
♪ It's all right It's all right, it's all right ♪
♪ It's all right It's all right ♪
♪ No one's got it all ♪
♪ All, all ♪
♪ Hung up and bent on a stranger ♪
♪  Just trying to swing a full-time ride ♪
♪ I never knew the cold hand of danger ♪
♪ Till I met this one and took it inside ♪
♪ Now I can't get near it ♪
去开房吧
Get a room! Really.
♪ My cover's blown ♪
♪ I walked in the rain like a drone ♪
♪ All the way to Marquette ♪
♪ The infinite pet ♪
♪ Oh, no ♪
♪ No, no, no, no, no ♪
♪ Cheaper than all your threats  No, no, no ♪
操
Shit.
我每5分钟给你打次电话  你没事吧
I've been calling you every five minutes. Are you okay?
- 我很好   - 你怎么了
I'm great. What happened to you?
- 我不想谈这个   - 你以前可不这样
I don't wanna talk about it. You always wanna talk about it.
- 这次不一样   - 别这样  走
Not this. Okay. Well, come on. Let's go.
- 去哪    - 今天是周四
Where are we going? It's Thursday!
这个人说 " 加油 "
This one says, "Go for it!"
这个说 " 你能做到 "
And this one says, "You can do it!"
我们有一系列富有灵感的照片贺卡
We have a whole line of inspirational photographic cards...
上面都是我的小猫 " 泡菜 "
featuring Pickles, my cat.
人们肯定会很喜欢
I think people will really enjoy them.
- 谢谢   - 干得不错
- Thank you. Good job, Rhoda.
挺有创意的
That's inspirational stuff.
好的  下一个是谁
Okay. Who's next?
好长时间没有慰问组的了
We haven't heard from Sympathy in a while.
- Hansen   - 哦
Hansen? Yeah?
冬日收藏系列  你有什么建议么
The Winter Collection? Do you have anything to contribute?
没有
Uh, no.
真没有
I really don't.
好吧
Okay.
过会再叫你   麦肯齐
We'll come back to you. Uh, McKenzie?
- 事实上  那些..  - 什么
Actually, you know what? Yes, Tom?
- 那只猫  我能说两句吗    - 当然
Can I say something about the cat? Well, okay.
那么 .. 这样
Yeah, uh, this is-
罗拉  我只是就事论事
And, Rhoda, no disrespect here,
但这真的很水
but, um, this is total shit.
- Tom    - " 加油 " 和 " 你能做到 "
Tom! "Go for it" and "You can do it"?
那不是创意  那是自杀
That's not inspirational. That's suicidal.
如果 " 泡菜 " 真的去寻找了  它就成死猫了
If Pickles goes for it right there, that's a dead cat.
骗人的  我们都是骗子
These are lies. We're liars.
想想吧   为什么人们买这些
Think about it. Why do people buy these things?
不是因为他们想说这些
It's not 'cause they want to say how they feel.
人们买贺卡  是因为他们不能或不敢  说出他们想说的
People buy cards 'cause they can't say how they feel, or they're afraid to.
我们提供服务  好让他们摆脱这些
We provide the service that lets them off the hook.
知道吗   这真扯蛋  让我们对美国人说实话吧
You know what? I say, to hell with it! Let's level with America.
起码让他们说出自己心里话
At least let them speak for themselves! Right?
看看  这些都是什么  写的什么
I mean, look! What- what is this? What does it say?
" 恭喜你喜得贵子 "   是吗
"Congratulations on your new baby." Right?
为什么不是 " 恭喜你鬼混出来的儿子出生
How 'bout, "Congratulations on your new baby.
认识你真高兴 " - 坐下 Hansen
- That's it for hanging out. Nice knowing you." - Sit down, Hansen.
这个呢  这个有爱心封面的  我知道里面是什么
How 'bout this one, with all the pretty hearts on the front? I know where this is going. Yep!
" 情人节快乐  甜心  我爱你 "
"Happy Valentine's Day, sweetheart. I love you."
真甜蜜  爱情多伟大
That sweet? Ain't love grand?
这就是我想说的
This is exactly what I'm talking about.
它到底是什么  爱情
What does that even mean, "love"?
你知道吗   你   谁知道
Do you know? Do you? Anybody?
Tom
Tom.
如果谁给我这样的卡片  万斯先生  我就吃了它
If somebody gave me this card, Mr. Vance, I would eat it.
就是这些卡片  电影  流行歌曲
It's- It's these cards, and the movies, and the pop songs-
它们该对所有的谎言负责
They're to blame for all the lies...
心痛  和所有的一切
and the heartache, everything.
我们有责任  我也有责任
And we're responsible. I'm responsible.
我认为我们在做错事
I think we do a bad thing here.
人们说出他们的感受  他们真实的感受
People should be able to say how they feel- how they really feel-
而不是让那些陌生人帮他们说
not, you know, some words that some strangers put in their mouths.
就像 " 爱 "
Words like "love"...
那没任何价值
that don't mean anything.
对不起  抱歉
Sorry. I'm sorry. I, uh-
我辞职
I quit. I'm-
这世界已经够扯蛋了  不需要我了
There's enough bullshit in the world without my help.
好了  下次我们做跑步练习
All right. Next we do running drills.
嗨  你又在描了
Hey, you're sketching again.
我只是乱画的
Yeah, well, just doodling.
Tom  我有20秒  告诉我   没事吧
Okay, Tom. We got 20 seconds. Talk to me. You okay?
没事  我很好
Yeah, I'm good. I'm great.
我那些朋友们都很喜欢你
You know, my friends are all in love with you.
就像俗话说
You know, it's like we said.
- 海里还有很多鱼  - 谢谢
Plenty of other fish in the sea. Thanks.
但也有食人鱼
But, uh, those are guppies.
对
Yeah.
- Tom  - 嗯
Hey, Tom? Mmm.
我知道你你认为  她就是你的命中注定
Look, I know you think that she was the one,
但我不觉得
but I don't.
你只记得那些好的那一面
Now, I think you're just remembering the good stuff.
下次  当你回首往事的时候..
Next time you look back, I, uh-
我真觉得你该好好想想了
I really think you should look again.
- 5点开始   - 你想去看吗
It's playing at 5:00. Do you wanna see it?
不知道 你该回去了
Um, I don't know. We could just go back to your place or-
不 我想去看  走吧
No, I really want to see it. Let's go.
♪ Time it was and what a time it was ♪
♪ It was ♪
♪ A time of innocence ♪
♪ A time of confidences ♪
- 你没事吧   - 没事
You okay? Yeah.
怎么了  电影..
What- what is it? The movie?
没事  我  我太傻了
It's nothing. I'm just- I'm just being stupid.
- 是吗   - 恩
Yeah? Yeah.
♪ Preserve your memories They're all that's left you ♪
没人听说过留兰香的世界
It pains me we live in a world...
真让人痛心
where nobody's heard of Spearmint.
- 我就没听说过他们   - 我把他们放进了我给你的混音碟里
I've never heard of them. I put 'em on that mix I made you.
第一首就是
They're track one.
哦  对
Oh, yeah.
那么  接下来干嘛
So, what do you wanna do?
我想我该走了
I think I'm just gonna call it a day.
不想一块吃晚饭吗   你不饿吗
You don't wanna get some dinner? Are you hungry?
你没事吧
You all right?
- 我只是有点累了   - 好吧
I'm just tired. Okay.
我有个好主意   薄烤饼
I got it. Pancakes!
♪ Oh, girl, I don't know all the reasons why ♪
♪ I found the answer looking in your eye ♪
♪ I go out walking all day long ♪
♪ Take away this lonely man Soon he will be gone ♪
♪ 'Cause I'll tell you everything ♪
♪ About living free ♪
♪ Yes, I can see you, girl ♪
♪ Can you see me ♪
♪ You don't need to know what I do all day ♪
♪ It's as much as I know watch it waste away ♪
♪ 'Cause I'll tell you everything ♪
♪ About living free ♪
♪ Yes, I can see you, girl ♪
♪ Can you see me ♪
♪ 'Cause I'll tell you everything ♪
♪ About being free ♪
嗨 Tom
Hey, Tom.
我想也许能在这见到你
I thought I might see you here.
你带我来过后  我就爱上这里了
I always loved this place, ever since you brought me.
那么 ..
So I, uh-
我是不是该说  恭喜了
I guess I should say congratulations.
除非你真心诚意
Only if you mean it.
好吧  既然这样..
Ah. Well, in that case-
最近怎么样
So, are you okay?
总会好起来的
I will be, eventually.
你 ..
You wanna- Hmm.
- 这件衣服真不错   - 谢谢
I like your suit. Ah, thanks.
看起来很精神
You look sharp.
- 你也是    - 谢谢
So do you. Thanks.
- 我辞职了    - 真的吗
I quit the office. You did?
我都不知道  真棒
I didn't know. That's great!
你..
And you, um-
你结婚了
you're married.
很难以置信  对吧
Yeah. It's crazy, huh?
- 以前你告诉过我  在 ..   - 我知道
You should have told me when we were at the- I know.
在婚礼上 我们跳舞的时候
You know, at the wedding when we were dancing.
- 当时他还没有向我求婚   - 但是他已经走进了你的生活
Well, he hadn't asked me yet. But he was in your life.
那你为什么还要跟我跳舞
Yeah. So why'd you dance with me?
因为我想
'Cause I wanted to.
你只是做你想做的  是吗
You just do what you want, don't you?
你从来不想做谁的女朋友
You never wanted to be anybody's girlfriend,
而你现在却是谁的妻子
and now you're somebody's wife.
我也很吃惊
Surprised me too.
我可能永远都理解不了
I don't think I'll ever understand that.
我是说  这不合情理
I mean, it doesn't make sense.
可事实就是这样
It just happened.
对  可这就是我理解不了的   怎么就这样了
Right, but that's what I don't understand. What just happened?
我只是一觉醒来   然后就明白了
I just- I just woke up one day, and I knew.
明白什么
Knew what?
那些和你在一起  一直不能确定的
What I was never sure of with you.
那真的很糟糕
You know what sucks?
当你发现你的信仰全是狗屎的时候
Realizing that everything you believe in is complete and utter bullshit.
- 真糟   - 什么
It sucks. What do you mean?
就是 命运 精神伴侣 真爱
Uh, you know, destiny, and soul mates, and true love,
那些童话 什么的
and all that childhood fairy tale nonsense.
你是对的  我应该听你的
You were right. L-I should have listened to you.
- 不   - 什么  你笑什么
No. Yeah. What? What are you smiling at?
- Tom   - 恩
Tom. What?
你这样看着我干嘛
What are you looking at me like that for?
那些..
Well, you know,
我觉得..
I guess it's 'cause...
我在店里看 道林·格雷
I was sitting in a deli and reading Dorian Gray
然后一个人走过来
and... a guy comes up to me...
问我那本书怎么样
and asked me about it,
现在  他是我的丈夫
and... now he's my husband.
然后呢
Yeah. And... so?
如果我去看看电影了呢
So, what if I'd gone to the movies?
或者我去吃午饭
What if I had gone somewhere else for lunch?
要么晚去了那10分钟呢
What if I'd gotten there 10 minutes later?
那好像..
It was-
那好像是注定好的
It was meant to be.
然后我就不停的想
And I just kept thinking,
- Tom是对的   - 不
Tom was right. No.
真的
Yeah, I did.
I did.
只是你的那个人不是我
It just wasn't me that you were right about.
我该走了
I should go.
看到你过的不错  我真的很高兴
But I'm really happy to see that you're doing well.
Summer
Summer!
祝你幸福
I really do hope that you're happy.
一年中的很多天都是很平凡的
Most days of the year are unremarkable.
开始 结束
They begin and they end...
没有留下任何回忆
with no lasting memories made in between.
大多数对生活没什么影响
Most days have no impact...
在一生中
on the course of a life.
5月23日  一个星期三
May 23 was a Wednesday.
- 你是来面试的吗   - 什么
Are you interviewing? Sorry?
你是来面试这个职位的吗
Are you interviewing for the position?
- 对  什么  你呢   - 也是
Oh, yeah. Why? Are you? Yeah.
嗯
Mm-hmm.
我的竞争者
My competition.
看来是的
It would appear.
有点尴尬
Yeah. So, a little awkward.
对
Yeah.
那么.. 祝你面试失败
Well, I hope you, um, don't get the job.
那我也祝你 面试失败
Well, I hope you don't get the job.
我以前见过你吗
Have I seen you before?
应该没有
Me? I don't think so.
你去过祈祷广场吗
Do you ever go to Angelus Plaza?
当然 那是我最喜欢的地方
Yes. That's, like, my favorite spot in the city.
除了那些停车场
Yeah. Okay. Except for the parking lots, but-
- 同意   - 对
Yeah. L- I agree. Yeah, yeah.
- 我见过你   - 真的
I think I've seen you there. Really?
我没见过你
Yeah. I haven't seen you.
你一定是在看其他什么
You must not have been looking.
如果说Tom学到了什么
If Tom had learned anything,
那就是你不能把那些意义归结于
it was that you can't ascribe great cosmic significance...
简单的小事
to a simple earthly event.
巧合  每时每刻都在发生
Coincidence. That's all anything ever is.
仅仅是巧合
Nothing more than coincidence.
Tom Hansen   恩
Tom Hansen. Yeah.
- 该你了   - 谢谢
Come on back. Thank you.
Tom 终于明白了  没有奇迹
Tom had finally learned there are no miracles.
没有那么多命运
There's no such thing as fate.
没什么注定的
Nothing is meant to be.
他懂了  很确定
He knew. He was sure of it now.
Tom-  抱歉
Tom was- Sorry. Um-
我忘了.. 等一下
I just left, uh- Can l- one second.
确信
He was pretty sure.
- 嘿   - 又是你
- Hey. - You again.
我只是觉得...
Yeah. I, uh, was just wondering...
也许在面试过后... 你..
if maybe after this, if, um, you-
是否可以一起去喝咖啡什么的
you want to get some coffee or something.
抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
结束后我可能要见一个人
I'm sort of supposed to meet someone after this.
好吧
Okay.
好的
Sure.
- 什么   - 没问题
What's that? Why not?
- 好  那我过会... 我等你
Okay. Well, then I'll just, uh- I'll wait for you-
- 我们再商量吧    - 我们再商量
we- We'll figure it out. We'll figure it out.
- 我是 Tom   - 很高兴认识你 我是 Autumn
- My name's Tom. - Nice to meet you. I'm Autumn.
♪ She's got you high and you don't even know yet ♪
♪ The sun's in the sky It's warming up your bare legs ♪
♪ And you can't deny you're looking for the sunset ♪
♪ She's got you high and you don't even know yet ♪
♪ It's the search for the time before it leaves without you ♪
♪ Have you lost your mind or has she taken all of yours too ♪
♪ What's this about I figured love would shine through ♪
♪ We've lost romance This world, its turns will see you through ♪
♪ open your mind Believe it's gonna come true ♪
♪ Keep romance alive and hope she's gonna tell you ♪
♪ What's this about I figured love would shine through ♪
♪ We've lost romance This world, its turns will see you through ♪
♪ open your mind Believe it's gonna come true ♪
♪ Keep romance alive and hope she's gonna tell you ♪
♪ She's got you high and you don't even know yet ♪
♪ The sun's in the sky It makes for happy endings ♪
♪ You can't deny you want a happy ending ♪
♪ What's this about I figured love would shine through ♪
♪ We've lost romance This world, its turns will see you through ♪
♪ open your mind Believe it's gonna come true ♪
♪ Keep romance alive and hope she's gonna tell you ♪
♪ She's got you high ♪
♪ What's this about I figured love would shine through ♪
♪ We've lost romance This world, its turns will see you through ♪
♪ open your mind Believe it's gonna come true ♪
♪ Keep romance alive and hope she's gonna tell you ♪
♪ What's this about I figured love would shine through ♪
♪ We've lost romance This world, its turns will see you through ♪
♪ open your mind Believe it's gonna come true ♪
♪ Keep romance alive and hope she's gonna tell you ♪
♪ She's got you high ♪